Chamila C. Dharmawardhan, Ph.D

□ ccdxz8@mail.umkc.edu

+1(509)201-7496

in LinkedIn

Google scholar

GitHub

Authorized to work in USA (Green Card holder)



Dedicated data scientist and a computational physicist with 14+ years of diverse experience in numerical simulation, scripting, data analysis and on HPC and other UNIX based systems. excellent team player with aptitude for planning and conducting interdisciplinary projects.

Skills & experience

languages:

Python, TSQL, C++, Java, Fortran, BASH, Perl, Mathematica

frameworks:

■ Anaconda, SciKit-learn, Pandas, numpy, scipy, TensorFlow, Keras, pytourch, beautifulsoup, GitHub

HPCC:

supercomputers (NERSC, XSEDE, ALCF). PBS, LSF ans SLURM batch queuing systems

Management:

■ Designed interdisciplinary research projects with diverse research collaborations effectively

Projects

Facial emotion recognition via deep learning (GitHub)

- · A facial expression recognition model to serve as a personal journal of emotion
- base CNN model developed with FER2013 Kaggle dataset (Tensorflow, Keras)
- Images scraped from google images(Selenium, bs4) and used transfer learning
- Django app build to service the CNN model and provide a journal app

Pneumonia prediction from X-ray images with CNN techniques (GitHub)

- CNN model developed with Kaggle dataset (Tensorflow, Keras)
- Hyper parameter tuning to increase accuracy.
- Transfer learning from VGG19 model to increase accuracy

Customer churn prediction of TelCo data via supervised learning (GitHub)

- CNN model developed with Kaggle dataset (SciKit-Learn, StatsModels)
- Customer churn prediction with logistic regression, Decision tree, Random forest, SVC, verity of boosting algorithms.
- Hyper parameter tuning to increase model accuracy and recall

Employment

Senior Research Associate, Illinois Institute of Technology

2019 - 2020

- Development FFT based algorithms for protein docking (numpy, pandas) to evaluate binding affinity of protein complexes
- Automated structure retrieval using **protein data bank API** and building scripts to streamline docking simulations of large databases

Post Doctoral Fellow, Georgetown University (2 Publications)

2017 - 2019

- Development of accurate and efficient computational methods for protein simulations
- building pythons scripts to streamline FF parameterization and simulation
- developed and implemented potential function for the SSMP model

Post Doctoral Fellow, University Colorado Boulder (3 Publications)

2016 - 2017

- Understanding corrosion of high temperature super-alloys in 4D: experimental/theoretical collaboration
- Developed Python tools for force fields building, data handling and visualization of results
- Automated calculations and visualizations via python and bash scripting

- Utilized ab initio simulation techniques to gain insight into structure at atomic level of cement based materials
- Developed efficient methods for thermo-mechanical simulations at high temperature (OpenMPI calculations)
- Troubleshoot software, manage group accounts in supercomputers and mentor students
- · Mentored three masters students, one undergraduate student, and one visiting scholar

Education

- 2020 Certificate, Data Science, Flatiron school of computing
- 2015 Ph.D., Physics, University of Missouri Kansas City
- 2008 MS., Physics, Central Michigan University
- BS., Physics/Mathematics, University of Colombo, Sri Lanka